Monika Høy

React Native Developer

About me

I'm Monika, originally from Denmark, but now based in Berlin. I've worked with React Native since 2021 where my love of plants resulted in a plant journal app. Shortly thereafter I got the unique opportunity to intern at an educational app, where I am now a mobile developer. I have a background in social science and localisation that I use to bring the user to the center, and to ensure clear and joyful communication with my coworkers.

Contact

monika.hoey@gmail.com LinkedIn

Experience

Equalista GmbH

Mobile Developer

Jan 2022 - present · Berlin

Responsible for builds, releases, developing new features and maintaining existing code

Junior Front end Developer

Sep 2021 - present · Berlin

- Developed a type your own answer feature for in-app questions
- Implemented nonSQL database structure
- Implemented categories for sorting learning courses

Front end Development Intern

June 2021 - Sep 2021 · Berlin

- Build a clickable session overview in courses screens
- Refactored text styles for unity across the app

Content Researcher

June 2020 - June 2021 · Berlin

- Researched, selected and wrote content for learning courses
- Worked closely with developers and designers in agile workflows

KAYAK

Localization Specialist for Danish Market

June 2021- present · Berlin

• Localize product and marketing content for KAYAK's websites and apps, and do linguistic quality and functionality checks (LQA)

Skills

JavaScript
TypeScript
HTML
CSS
Communication

Tools

React Native Expo CLI Figma Firebase Prismic

Languages

Danish · Native English · Native proficiency German · Intermediate (B2)

Education

Prof. Diploma UX Design Glasgow University · 2020

MSc Spatial Designs & Society Roskilde University · 2018

BA arts in European Ethnology Copenhagen University · 2013

Wundermedia GmbH

Online Editor & Translator

July 2019 July 2020 · Berlin

- Optimized and edited content for Microsoft News' website at the international news hub, Berlin via user engagement analysis and SEO
- Localized and translated articles from English to Danish

Copenhagen Municipality

Project employee to improve city life

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019 · Copenhagen

- Planned and executed a project focused on liveable cities at Kultorvet Copenhagen
- Analyzed the use of public spaces via interviews, workshops and surveys and created user-centered design solutions

Office Worker

Feb 2011 - Nov 2018 · Copenhagen

• Student worker at the logistics team at Copenhagen Main Library

Other projects

Grow - a plant journal

React Native and Expo developer

2021 · Berlin

- Developed and built an app in React Native and Expo
- Designed and developed all app screens, React Navigation and NonSQL database structure